A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Central Index FA736
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Central Index
1950-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA736
196 Microform Reels
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for scholarly research.
Ford Foundation
- Central Index Cards, 1950-1974; 1; 108 Microform Reels; The Central Index cards for 1950-1974 are housed on 108 reels of 16mm microfilm, numbered Reel 001 to Reel 108. There are approximately 253,900 cards in this series.
  Scope and Contents
  The Ford Foundation’s Central Index cards covering the years 1950-1974 provide indexing to four types of records in the Ford Foundation archive:
  Ford Foundation records, Grants (FA732)
  Ford Foundation records, Projects (FA733)
  Ford Foundation records, Log files (FA734)
  Ford Foundation records, General Correspondence (FA735)
  Indexed terms include organizational or institutional names, personal names, places, and subjects.
  - A - African C (Reel 1)
  - African D - ALK (Reel 2)
  - ALL - American L (Reel 3)
  - American M - AQ (Reel 4)
  - AR - ARZ (Reel 5)
  - AS - AU (Reel 6)
  - AV - BARJ (Reel 7)
  - BARK - BED (Reel 8)
  - BEE - BERR (Reel 9)
  - BERT - BLI (Reel 10)
  - BLO - BOUQ (Reel 11)
  - BOUR - BRIS (Reel 12)
  - BRIT - BUH (Reel 13)
  - BUI - BY (Reel 14)
  - C - CAM (Reel 15)
  - CAN - CAS (Reel 16)
  - CAT - CHAM (Reel 17)
  - CHAN - CHM (Reel 18)
  - CHO - CLE (Reel 19)
  - CLI - COL (Reel 20)
  - COM - CONL (Reel 21)
  - CONN - COT (Reel 22)
  - COU - CUP (Reel 23)
  - CUR - DAV (Reel 24)
  - DAW - DEQ (Reel 25)
  - DER - DM (Reel 26)
  - DO - DUM (Reel 27)
  - DUN - EDL (Reel 28)
  - EDM - ELM (Reel 29)
  - ELN - EU (Reel 30)
  - EV - FED (Reel 31)
  - FEE - FIS (Reel 32)
  - FIT - FORD (Reel 33)
  - FORE - FRID (Reel 34)
  - FRIE - GAR (Reel 35)
  - GAS - GIR (Reel 36)
  - GIS - GOS (Reel 37)
  - GOT - GREF (Reel 38)
  - GREG - GY (Reel 39)
  - H - HAQ (Reel 40)
  - HAR - HAT (Reel 41)
  - HAU - HEP (Reel 42)
  - HER - HOD (Reel 43)
  - HOE - HOT (Reel 44)
  - HOU - HW (Reel 45)
  - HY - INE (Reel 46)
  - INF - INS (Reel 47)
  - INT - IQ (Reel 48)
  - IR - JAO (Reel 49)
  - JAP - JOL (Reel 50)
  - JON - KAO (Reel 51)
  - KAP - KEW (Reel 52)
  - KEY - KN (Reel 53)
  - KO - L (Reel 54)
  - LA - LAT (Reel 55)
  - LAU - LEN (Reel 56)
  - LEO - LIND (Reel 57)
  - LINE - LOT (Reel 58)
  - LOU - Mc C (Reel 59)
  - Mc D - Mc W (Reel 60)
  - M - MAQ (Reel 61)
  - MAR - MAS (Reel 62)
  - MAT - MEM (Reel 63)
  - MEN - MH (Reel 64)
  - MI - MIM (Reel 65)
  - MIN - MON (Reel 66)
  - MOO - MT (Reel 67)
  - MU - NAH (Reel 68)
  - NAI - NAT (Reel 69)
  - NAV - New R (Reel 70)
  - New S - NOO (Reel 71)
  - NOR - OE (Reel 72)
  - OF - ORS (Reel 73)
  - ORT - PAM (Reel 74)
  - PAN - PEM (Reel 75)
  - PEN - PH (Reel 76)
  - PI - POP (Reel 77)
  - POR - PS (Reel 78)
  - PU - RAL (Reel 79)
  - RAM - REK (Reel 80)
  - REL - RIU (Reel 81)
  - RIV - ROR (Reel 82)
  - ROS - RZ (Reel 83)
  - S - SAM (Reel 84)
  - SAN - SCE (Reel 85)
  - SCHA - SCHZ (Reel 86)
  - SCI - SG (Reel 87)
  - SHA - SHZ (Reel 88)
  - SI - SJ (Reel 89)
  - SK - SN (Reel 90)
  - SOA - SOZ (Reel 91)
  - SP - STA (Reel 92)
  - STE - STRA (Reel 93)
  - STRE - SWE (Reel 94)
  - SWI - TD (Reel 95)
  - TE - THI (Reel 96)
  - THO - TRB (Reel 97)
  - TRE - TZ (Reel 98)
  - UA - UN (Reel 99)
  - P - VEP (Reel 100)
  - ER - WAK (Reel 101)
  - AL - WAS (Reel 102)
  - AT - WER (Reel 103)
  - ES - WH (Reel 104)
  - I - WIM (Reel 105)
  - IN - WL (Reel 106)
  - O - X (Reel 107)
  - Y- Z (Reel 108)
- Central Index Cards, 1975-1996; 2; 68 Microform Reels; The Central Index, 1975-1996 is housed on 68 reels of 16mm microfilm, and numbered Roll 1 to Roll 68. There are approximately 163,700 cards in this series.
  The Ford Foundation’s Central Index cards for the years 1975-1996 provide access to three file-types in the Ford Foundation Archive:
  Ford Foundation records, Grant files (FA732)
  Ford Foundation records, Log files (grant and project proposals (FA734)
  Ford Foundation records, General Correspondence files (FA735)
  These three file-types are indexed by organizational/institutional names, personal names, and places.
  - A Better Chance (ABC) - Adnyana (Reel 1)
  - ADO - AI Group Inc. (Reel 2)
  - Aid to Families - American Music (Reel 3)
  - American Music - Arrowsmith, R. (Reel 4)
  - Arroyo Alejandres, J. - Bahuguna, V. (Reel 5)
  - Bai, D. - Be, X. (Reel 6)
  - Beach, D. - Billington, J. (Reel 7)
  - Bir Zeit Univ. - Bramsen, M. (Reel 8)
  - Branch, A. - Burke, F. (Reel 9)
  - Burke, D. - Cardoso, R. (Reel 10)
  - Cardoso, R. - Center for Regional Investigation (Reel 11)
  - Center for Regional Planning - Chicago United (Reel 12)
  - Chicana Rights Project - Cobey, P. (Reel 13)
  - Coble, C. - Connell, G. (Reel 14)
  - Connell, J - Cruz, C. (Reel 15)
  - Cruz, C. - Degbey, S. (Reel 16)
  - Debt Service Reserve Fund - Dirasse, L. (Reel 17)
  - Dire, M. - Ebzery, J. (Reel 18)
  - Eccel, C. - Esiet, N. - (Reel 19)
  - Eskin, R. - Ferraro, V. (Reel 20)
  - Ferraz, E. - Foundation for the Graduate (Reel 21)
  - Foundation for the Graduate - Garcia, P. (Reel 22)
  - Garcia, P. - Godinez, V. (Reel 23)
  - Godine Windhorst, C. - Greenhouse Warming (Reel 24)
  - Greening, P. - Hamzah, W. (Reel 25)
  - Han, D. - Healy, R. (Reel 26)
  - Healy, T. - Hoiley, I. (Reel 27)
  - Holley, J. - Ibrahim, K. (Reel 28)
  - Ibrahim, K. - Institute for Research on Public (Reel 29)
  - Institute School of the Future - Inter Press Service (Reel 30)
  - Iverson, D. - JSI Research & Training Institute (Reel 31)
  - Joint Committee on Eastern Europe - Kauffman, M. (Reel 32)
  - Kaufman, A. - Kirumbi, L. (Reel 33)
  - Kisamba, M. - Lafaraa (Reel 34)
  - Legters, L. - La Forge, P. (Reel 35)
  - Le Guennec-Coppens - Locally Based Intermediaries (Reel 36)
  - Locally Funded Housing Programs - McGinnis, P. (Reel 37)
  - McGinnis, R. - Mangahas, R. (Reel 38)
  - Mandaldas, L. - Maxwell (Reel 39)
  - May, B. - Middle East (Reel 40)
  - Middle East - Moore, M. (Reel 41)
  - Moore, M. - Muller, H. (Reel 42)
  - Muller, H. - National Legal Services (Reel 43)
  - National Legal Services - New York University (Reel 44)
  - New York University - Oaxaca State (Mexico) (Reel 45)
  - Oba of Benin - Ortega, C. (Reel 46)
  - Ota, R. - Pavan, C. (Reel 47)
  - Pavane, M. - Pinchon, B. (Reel 48)
  - Pinchot Institute for Conservation - Pressley, C. (Reel 49)
  - Pro Bono Directory - Ramusack, B. (Reel 50)
  - Ran, S. - Rice, V. (Reel 51)
  - Rich, A. - Rodenberg (Reel 52)
  - Rodriguez, C. - Saldivar, R. (Reel 53)
  - Saldivar-Sali, T. - Schmidt, E. (Reel 54)
  - Schmidt, G. - Shannon, T. (Reel 55)
  - Shannon, W. - Sintta, S. (Reel 56)
  - Sinha, S. - Sopanasrir, S. (Reel 57)
  - Sopelak, V. - Steinberg, J. (Reel 58)
  - Steinberg, J. - Svendsen, M. (Reel 59)
  - Svenson, E. - Thaim, A. (Reel 60)
  - Thain, G. - Trimble, P. (Reel 61)
  - TRW Inc. - Urban Recovery Legal Assistance Project (Reel 62)
  - Urban Redevelopment - Vlisides, C. (Reel 63)
  - Vodai, L. - Weiner, M. (Reel 64)
  - Weiner, M. - Wilson, H. (Reel 65)
  - Wilson, H. - World Wide Fund for Nature-India (Reel 66)
  - World Wide Fund for Nature-India - Zemsky, R. (Reel 67)
  - Zen, N. - Zysman, J. (Reel 68)
- Central Index Subject Cards, 1975-1996; 3; 7 Microform Reels; This series of Subject Cards is housed on 7 reels of 16mm microfilm, numbered Roll 1 to Roll 7. There are approximately 9,900 cards in this series.
  The Central Index, 1975-1996 - Subject cards provide indexing to the same three file types as the Central Index cards:
  Grant files (FA732)
  Log files (grant and project proposals (FA734)
  General Correspondence files (FA735)
  However, the majority of files indexed in this series of cards are Grant files.
  Other Finding Aids
  A digitized version of the Subject Cards is available to RAC archivists (except for Roll 2, which is missing from the digitized version). Please consult an Archivist for details.
  - Aboriginal - Computers (Reel 1)
  - Conference - Education (Reel 2)
  - Education - Hispanics (Reel 3)
  - Hispanics - Management (Reel 4)
  - Management - National Resources (Reel 5)
  - Public Welfare - Social Sciences (Reel 6)
  - Social Sciences - Youth (Reel 7)
- Log Books, 1951-1981; 4; 3 Microform Reels
  - Log Files, 1951-1981
    The log Book for Log Files (Grant and Project proposals) lists all Ford Foundation Log Files from L51-001 to L81-168.
    - L51-001 to L72-310 (Reel 109)
    - L73-001 to L81-168 (Reel 110)
  - Grants and Projects, 1951-1974
    The log book for Grants and Projects lists Ford Foundation Project files, A-001 to A-1000, B-001 to B-499; Grant files, from PA53-001 to PA53-088 (including corresponding pre-1953 Project#); NY Fund projects NY-001 to NY-166; Project files B-500 to B-1000, C-1 to C-1000, D-1 to D-1000, E-1 to E-237; Grant files PA53-001 to PA74-985.
    The Fund File Index reproduces a log book listing all Ford Foundation:
    - Project Files, A-001 to A-1000, 1950-1952 (Reel 111)
    - Project Files, B-001 to B-499, 1952-1955 (Reel 111)
    - Grants, from PA53-001 to PA53-088, 1953 (Reel 111)
    - NY Fund projects: NY-001 to NY-166, 1951-1954 (Reel 111)
    - Project Files, B-500 to B-1000, 1955-1956 (Reel 111)
    - Project Files, C-1 to C-1000, 1956-1959 (Reel 111)
    - Project Files, D-1 to D-1000, 1959-1963 (Reel 111)
    - Project Files, E-1 to E-237, 1963-1964 (Reel 111)
    - Grants, from PA53-001 to PA74-985, 1953-1974 (Reel 111)
- Master Cards, 1951-1965; 5; 6 Microform Reels
  - Fund Files, 1951-1963 (Reel 112)
    The Master Cards - Fund Files provide detailed description of Fund Files "A" through "X".
    - "A" Miscellaneous Grants, including Michigan Fund (Reel 112)
    - "B" Fund for the Advancement of Education (Reel 112)
      Related Materials
      See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants, 05300036 (PA53-36), The Fund For The Advancement Of Education.
    - "C" Fund for Adult Education (Reel 112)
      See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants 05300035 (PA53-35), The Fund For Adult Education.
    - "D" Exchange of Persons (Reel 112)
    - "E" East European Fund, Inc. (Reel 112)
      See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants, 05300031 (PA53-31), East European Fund, Inc.
    - "G" Fund for the Republic (Reel 112)
      See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants 05300037 (PA53-37), The Fund For The Republic, Inc.
    - "H" President’s Authority (Reel 112)
    - "K" Resource Conservation Program (Reel 112)
    - "L" Intercultural Publications, Inc (Reel 112)
      See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants, 05300033 (PA53-33), Intercultural Publications, Inc.
    - "M" Board on Overseas Training and Research (Reel 112)
    - "P" Public Affairs Program (Reel 112)
    - "R" Education Program (Reel 112)
    - "S" Research and Training in Mental Health (Reel 112)
    - "U" Humanities and Arts Program (Reel 112)
    - "X" Program in Science and Engineering (Reel 112)
  - Projects, 1951-1964
    The Master Cards - Projects provides information on Project Files NY-001 to NY-166; A-1 to A-745; B-1 to B-1000; C-1 to C-1000; D-1 to D-1000; E-1 to E-199.
    Arrangement
    Master Cards - Projects are arranged alpha-numerically by the Project file number.
    - NY-1 - NY-166 (Reel 112)
    - A-1 - A-745 (Reel 112)
    - B-1 - B-1000 (Reel 113)
    - C-1 - C-1000 (Reel 113)
    - D-1 - D-1000 (Reel 114)
    - E-1 - E-199 (Reel 114)
  - Grants, 1953-1965 (Reel 115-118)
    The Master Cards - Grants provide information on Ford Foundation Grant files numbered PA53-1 to PA65-350. Each Master Card provides information regarding a grant’s Name, Institution, Remittor, Recom. By, Purpose, Request, & Action.
    Master Cards - Grants are arranged numerically by the Program Action (Grant) number.
    - PA53-1 to PA56-343 (Reel 115)
    - PA57-1 to PA58-404 (Reel 116)
    - PA59-1 to PA61-385 (Reel 117)
    - PA62-1 to PA65-380 (Reel 118)
- Acronym Cards, 6; 3 Microform Reels; The Acronym Series cards are housed on 3 reels of 16mm microfilm, numbered Roll 1 to Roll 3.
  Arranged alphabetically by acronym.
  The cards provide the full title of an institution/organization. These cards do not provide indexing to any of the file types in the Ford Foundation archives.
  - AAA - GYC (Reel 1)
  - HABDEV - SEPIA (Reel 2)
  - SEPM - WEDO (Reel 3)